The ship of hope, Espoir.
希望の船 エスポワール
それは借金を抱え
A gambling ship where those
desperate in debt gather.
行き詰まった者たちを集めた
ギャンブル船
そこで開催された勝負
And that's where
Ito Kaiji...
限定ジャンケンに挑んだ伊藤開司
...joins the game of Restricted
Rock Paper Scissors.
But early in the game,
しかし 開始早々
その寿命ともいうべき星を
he lost his stars which is
equivalent to his life gauge.
立て続けに失ってしまう
I'll see you later.
Thanks for the stars.
ほな 俺はこれで ごちそうさん
In this hopeless situation,
彼はこの劣悪な状況の中
２人の男 古畑 安藤と
運命共同体を組み
he teamed up with 2 guys,
Furuhata and Ando,
生き残りへの道を踏み出す
to try to create
a way to survive.
３人合わせた手持ちのカードは
チョキ４枚 パー１枚
The cards they have are
4 Scissors and 1 Paper.
何か俺 希望が わいてきました
Somehow I'm starting
to feel more hopeful now.
It's better to have three of us
than one. We're friends, right?
１人よりは３人
仲間ですよね 俺たち
救えねえやつ
Hopeless fool! We're still three
pieces of useless trash.
しょせん俺たち
クズ３人じゃねえか
状況は大して変わってねえんだよ
この甘ったれが！
The situation isn't
any better!
You stupid naive idiot!
お？お前 カード１枚 どうした？
What happened to
one of your cards?
Oh, Ando asked me
for it, so I...
ああ… 安藤さんが１枚
持たせてくれって言うから
何？渡したのか？
- What?! You gave it to him?
- Yeah.
バカ野郎　分からねえのか
Idiot! Don't you get it?
やつは星２つでカード０
He has 2 stars and
no cards at all!
たった１枚のカードが
欲しい状態だったんだぞ
A card is exactly
what he wants!
そのカードが手に入ったら
勝負に行くに決まってるだろ
Once he has one, he'll
definitely go try his luck!
そんな…
やつを捜すんだ
No way...
Find him.
はい
O-Okay!
どこだ 野郎　どこだ？
Where... Where's that fool?
カイジさん　あそこです
Kaiji! Over there!
待ちやがれ　安藤
何だ お前？
Stop right there!
Ando!
What's with you?!
いや…
勝負の邪魔をするな
Nothing.
Don't interfere with the game!
そうじゃなくて…
下がれ 下がれ
That's not it!
Get back! Get back!
Kaiji!
カイジさん
安藤！
Ando!
チェック
安藤
Check!
Ando!
Set!
セット
オープン
Open!
やった　チョキなら あいこだ
Alright! It's a draw
if it's Scissors!
星２つなら安藤も抜けやしない
With 2 stars, Ando won't be
able to leave us!
N-No way...
バ… バカな
Game
すいません　勘弁してください
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
I wanted to get 5 stars
for everyone...
何とかみんなの星を
５つにしようと思って…
うそつけ！勝ったら俺たちを
裏切るつもりだったんだろうが
Liar! You were going to
betray us if you win, right?!
そんな！誤解です
It's a misunderstanding!
Kaiji! Let's get rid of this guy!
This traitor!
カイジさん　こいつもう
切りましょうよ　こんな裏切り者
Kaiji, please trust me!
カイジさん　信じてください
俺 裏切る気なんて
毛ほどもなかった
I have no intention
of betraying you!
見苦しい
I can't bear the sight
of you!
あんまり人をナメるな
Don't take people for fools!
俺が止めに入った時
お前はチェック宣言前
I had to stop you before
you declared check.
まだ勝負はやめられたのに
やめなかった
You could have stopped
if you wanted to.
There's no such thing
as trust there.
信じろも くそもねえ
勝っていたら 俺たちを切っていた
If you won,
then we will be cut off.
それだけは疑いようがねえのさ
There's no doubt about that.
だが安心しろ　切らねえ
どうしてですか？
But don't worry.
I won't get rid of you.
Why not?!
悪しきを切ってたら 団結はねえ
カイジさん
We won't be united if
we remove the bad parts.
Kaiji!
もし安藤を切れば理由はどうあれ
その事実が足かせとなり
If I cut Ando off,
regardless of the reason,
we won't benefit from it.
いよいよとなれば こいつは
自分を切るやつだと考える
You'll begin to think that I'll cut
you off when something happens.
３人で１単位
運命共同体と誓ったのに
Not long after we vowed
to share a common destiny,
その舌の根も乾かぬうちに
グループの心はバラバラ
the group starts to fall apart
just like that.
So we can't cut him off...
even if we want to.
だから切らねえ
切りたくても切らねえんだ
あ ありがとうございます
T-Thank you.
俺 ここからは頑張って協力して…
I'll try my best to assist you
from now on...
協力じゃねえ！
It's not assisting !
１頭のライオンが３つに分かれて
生きていけるかって言ってんだ
If a lion is split into three,
can it survive?!
Darn it!
くそったれが！
くそっ　くそっ
Darn! Darn! Darn!
かろうじてグループは維持された
The group managed to
keep together,
しかし 状況は星を１つ減らし窮地
but their situation seems
grimmer now with one less star.
All they have left
are these 4 Scissors.
手元に残されたのは
この４枚のチョキのカードのみ
たった１枚のパーを使っちまって
By using up the only Paper
card we have,
お前のせいで
このバランスの悪いカードで
it's all your fault that we
have to survive...
乗り切らなきゃいけないんだぞ
...with these unbalanced cards!
B-But it's not all my fault that the
rest of the cards are unbalanced.
の 残りのカードの
バランスが悪いのは
俺だけの責任じゃないっす
何？
- What?!
- It's your cards...
もともと古畑さんが持ってた
...that are unbalanced
right from the start!
カードのバランスにも
問題があったわけで
お前！言うにこと欠いて！
もう１度 言ってみろ
You! How dare you!
Try saying that again!
Wait.
待て
カイジさん
Kaiji...
Be quiet.
黙ってろ
バランス？バランスだ
Balance? It's the balance...
The cards keep crossing
one another in his head.
幾度となくカードが交差する
その無限の交差の中
In that infinite crossing,
a thought began to form.
編み込まれていく ある思考
それによって
解きほぐされていく結び目
And with that,
a knot is untied...
勝てる　いや 勝てるかも
We could win! We might
actually be able to win...
The door which
was closed...
開きそうにもなかった扉が今
きしみつつ動き出した
...now seemed to
open up a crack,
そこから差し込む光明
letting a beam of light
shine through.
捨てたもんじゃねえ
俺たちにもまだツキがある
All is not lost yet!
Luck is still with us!
There's no time to waste!
グズグズしちゃいられねえ
What?
分担して動こう
俺は金で星を仕入れてくる
Let's split up.
I'll go buy the stars.
その間にお前たちは
Meanwhile, you guys go search
for a man with my description!
これから俺が言う条件の男を
探してくれ
条件？
Description?
The description Kaiji
gave was...
カイジの言う条件とは…
まず手持ちのカードが
９枚の男を見つけ
Firstly, a man with 9 cards.
Then check his deck
with 2 duels.
その後の２回の勝負を
チェックする
順番はどうあれ
グーとチョキを使っていること
Whatever the sequence, make sure
he used Rock and Scissors.
言い換えれば９枚のカードのうち
That means, a man who
used Rock and Scissors,
グーとチョキの２枚を使い
and who is left with 7 cards
out of his 9 cards.
残り７枚となった男
むろんカイジの思いついた策は
決して必勝の策ではない
Of course, the plan
Kaiji thought of...
...was not a foolproof plan
to winning.
Kaiji knows that best.
それはカイジ自身が分かっている
当然 星１つでは挑めない
And furthermore,
one star is not enough.
勝負の前に星を２つに戻すことが
必須条件なのだ
He'll need to go back to having
2 stars before he duels.
But this proved to be
the most difficult.
しかし これが至難
はあっ？ダメダメ
What? No way!
星を売れ？何 言ってんの
冗談じゃないぜ
Sell my stars?
What are you talking about?
Don't kid me!
１千万なら考えてやってもいいぜ
I'll consider it for 10 million!
誰１人 まともな交渉には応じない
No one took him seriously.
が それも無理ないのだ
But it can't be helped.
まだ皆 勝負の渦中
時期が悪かったのだ
Everyone is still in
the middle of the game.
The timing is bad.
もう１～２時間 過ぎれば
星の余裕が確定する者が現れ
After one or two hours,
those with extra stars
will appear.
交渉も成り立ったろう
and they will be open
to negotiations.
嫌だ… やめてくれ
誰か助けてくれ
No! Stop! Somebody help me!
No! Help me!
嫌だ 嫌だ　助けてくれ
Somebody! Help!
誰か助けて！
These guys are crazy...
こいつら… 狂ってやがる
カイジさん
Kaiji!
There's a man who is
left with 7 cards!
今 ７枚になったばかりの男が
いました
今 安藤が見張ってます
星のほうは？
Ando's watching him now. How are
you doing with the stars?
I haven't bought
them yet.
それが… まだ買えてねえ
そんな… どうするんです？
No way! What should we do?
At this rate...!
グズグズしてると…
分かってる
I know!
Not many people who fulfil
the conditions are left...
条件をそろえた男が
そう何人も残ってるはずねえ
He might be the last one...
ひょっとしたら最後の１人
千載一遇のチャンス　だが…
This is our best bet!
But...! But...!
だが…
勝利への道
その１歩目が途切れている
The path to victory is blocked
at the very first step.
To walk this path,
you must not dodge.
この道を行くには
身を翻さなくてはならない
No matter how frightening it is,
you must not back out.
どんなに恐ろしくとも
ここは臆してはならない道
これは飛べる距離なんだ
This is the distance
I have to leap!
Let's go!
行こう
カイジさん　こっちです
Kaiji! Over there!
臆さない　ただ行くだけ
No fear... Just move forward!
安藤
どいつだ？
Ando! Which one is he?
あいつです
ソファーに座ってる男
That guy! That guy on the sofa.
なるほど こりゃ好都合だ
I see, this is convenient
for us!
Oh?
Did he avoid playing with
those with many stars?
やつは星の多い相手の勝負を
避けてなかったか？
W-Well...
ええ？ええ… 確かに
Yeah, he did seem to be avoiding
games with those people.
星の多いやつとは
明らかに勝負を避けてました
どうして分かったんですか？
How did you know?
やつが星１つの男と
勝負してたのを見たんだ
I saw him playing with
a guy with one star.
普通 星１つの相手とは
戦いたくないぜ
You usually won't want to play
with someone with one star.
何か自分の手で
破滅に突き落とすみたいで
You'll feel bad if
you were the one...
気が引けるだろ？
...who pushed the guy
off the cliff, right?
でも やつが星１つの男に
勝った時の顔は
But he looked like he was
gloating when he won.
してやったりって感じだった
星が多い相手を嫌がるのは
And why does he avoid
those with many stars?
恐らくやつの戦略は
I fear his strategy is like that
of a contrarian in roulette.
ルーレットなんかでよくある
逆張り
He only plays against...
限定ジャンケンなら
星１つか２つの
...those with 1 or 2 stars in
Unrestricted Rock Paper Scissors.
落ち目のやつのみを相手にする
そうやって勝ちを拾う
弱ってる相手専門のハンター
He's a hunter who seeks out
weaker opponents to beat.
He's just like a hyena!
ハイエナ野郎ってことさ
星１つの俺がやつの傍らで
頭でも抱えてりゃ
If I, with my one star,
look distressed in front of him,
向こうから声をかけてくるさ
I'm sure he'll challenge me.
そ… そんなやつ相手にして
大丈夫なんですか？
A-Are you sure you'll be fine
against someone like him?
Yes. He's the ideal opponent!
いや やつこそ理想の相手だ
What?!
カードを確認してる
やつの余裕の表情を見ても分かる
Judging from his relaxed
expression when he checks his cards,
やつは間違いなくバランス派だ
バランス派？
he definitely belongs to
the balanced type!
Balanced type?
I'll be back.
いってくる
どういうことなんすかね
What did he mean?
たぶんカードのことだろう
I guess he meant the cards.
次に何を出すか
唯一 ｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾙできるところだからな
The only type who can control
what card to play next.
確かに…
じゃあ古畑さんはどうして
Indeed. So...
Why are you left with
3 Scissors and 1 Paper?
チョキ３枚 パー１枚
残したんですか？
え？考えてもしょうがないから
I thought it was useless
to dwell on it,
行き当たりばったりで
適当に出してただけだよ
so I just played my cards
at random.
ええっ？普通もっと
バランスを考えますよ
What?! But won't you usually
think about balance?
バランス？
いえ その要するに
Balance?
Yeah, to put it simply,
今 僕たちが困っている
one should avoid being left with 4
Scissors cards like what we have now.
チョキ４枚っていう状態を
避けるっていうか…
Usually you'd want to leave
yourself with an alternative...
普通 カードをギリギリまで
選択することができるように
あまり偏った残し方は
しないっていうか…
...instead of an unbalanced
hand.
もし自分のカードが偏っていて
If your cards are of only
one kind,
そのことが相手に知られたら
目も当てられないですよ
and your opponents find out,
then there's no way to win.
だ だからたぶん…
安藤！
So that's why...
Ando!
それだよ　カイジさんは
What?!
That's it!
Kaiji figured out
that guy has 2 Rock,
やつの手持ちカード７枚のうち
グー チョキ パー
2 Scissors and 2 Paper
among his 7 cards!
それぞれ２枚ずつは
あると読んだんだ
なるほど
問題は残る１枚が何かだけど
I see.
But what's the last card?
あ！そうだよ　分かりきったこと
That's right! I know!
パーだよ
- The answer is Paper !
- What?!
In a hand of 9 cards,
手持ちの９枚のカードのうち
２回の勝負で グーとチョキの
カードを使用すると
after using a Rock and
Scissors in 2 duels,
この７枚となる
バランス重視の者であれば
you'll end up with
7 cards like this.
Those who place emphasis
on balance...
次にグーやチョキのカードを
使用する場合
...will avoid using a Rock
or Scissors next.
カードが偏ることとなる
Thus they'll use a Paper
card instead...
ゆえにパーのカードを
使用するという公算が成立する
...to avoid upsetting the balance
of their deck.
危機的状況の中で
カイジは探り当てた
Kaiji had sensed it
in this crisis.
勝利へのタイトロープ
A tightrope towards victory.
しかし しょせんは
仮定で塗り固めた理
But it's just theory based on
assumptions after all.
相手の気まぐれで
たやすく破綻する
The opponent's fickleness can
easily topple that theory.
Now Kaiji's leaving his destiny
今 この吹けば飛ぶような理に
カイジたちは自らの運命を
預けようとしている
in the hands
of this fragile reasoning.
チェック　セット
Check!
Set!
カイジさん
Kaiji...
Open!
オープン
頼む 神様　１度だけ…
Please, god!
Just once...
Just this once...
ここ１度だけ
渡らせてください
Let us cross this
flimsy bridge!
この か弱い橋を！
カイジさん
ま… まさか
Kaiji!
D-Don't tell me...
カイジさん
そんな…
Kaiji!
No way...
え？てことは…
This means...
その…
That...
He did it!
やったあ
勝った　勝ったぞ
He won! He won!
星１つで大騒ぎしやがって
Making such a fuss over
one star...
Stop!
待て
戻れ　席に着け
Come back! Sit down!
What?
もう ひと勝負だ
One more round!
ちょ… ちょっと待ってよ
カイジさん
W-Wait a minute, Kaiji.
深呼吸 深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
Don't get too worked up.
ダメだよ 熱くなっちゃ
勝ったから勢いに
乗りたいってのは分かるけどさ
I know you want to capitalise
on your winning streak.
何だ 分かってるじゃねえか
So you do understand.
分かってんなら
お前らこそ深呼吸してみろ
If you get it, you guys
should take deep breath!
俺たちはまだまだ
星を取っていかなきゃならねえ
We still have many more
stars to obtain!
勝ったら前へ…
当たり前のことだろ
Push forward if you win.
That should be the way!
で… でもカイジさん
B-But Kaiji...
今のやつは次に何 出すかもう…
You won't know what
he'll put out next.
いいから任せとけ　必ず勝つ
Just leave it to me!
I'll win this!
ははーん　こいつら
緊急避難のように体制を組んだ
These losers are clinging to each
other like refugees in a crisis.
クズの集まり
ツキに見放された
３人組ってわけだ
They're just a 3-man group
abandoned by Lady Luck.
どうなんだ？
What do you say?
いいだろう　受けてやるよ
Alright.
I accept!
よし
Right!
流れが読めねえ 調子乗りが
Arrogant idiots who can't
read the flow.
お前らに２連勝があるかよ
There will be no 2 straight
wins for you!
踏みつぶしてやる
I'll crush you to bits!
チェック
何でだよ
Check.
Why?!
冷静に勝負を考えてる人だと
思ったのに
I thought he was a cool-headed
guy bent on winning!
セット
Set!
B-But...
でも確かに
じっくり理詰めで勝負してたら
It's true that it's impossible
to get 9 stars...
とても時間内に
９個の星なんて無理
...if we go around
playing like that.
カイジさんはそれを実感したんだ
Kaiji understands that.
勢いに乗って奇跡の連勝に
走り出さない限り…
Without a miraculous
winning streak,
俺たちに生き残りはない
we won't be able to survive!
オープン
Open!
頼む　もう１度 パー！
Please! One more time!
Darn it!
くそっ
バカが… 当然の結果じゃねえか
Fool! That's obvious
from the start!
２度続けて同じカードで
勝てるとでも思ってんのかよ
Do you think you could win with
the same cards twice in a row?
ん？待てよ　てことは…
Wait! This means...
カイジさん　行こう
Kaiji, let's go.
Right.
おい
Hey!
Yeah?
もうひと勝負だ
One more game.
What?
さっきはお前の望みを
聞いてやったんだ
I did what you asked
just now.
今度はそっちが
俺の望みを聞く番だぜ
Now it's your turn
to listen to me.
カイジさん　行きましょう
Kaiji, let's go.
相手にすることないです
There's no need to listen to him.
だから お前らはダメなんだ
If so, then you guys
are doomed!
１人じゃ何も決められないクズが
Garbage that can't even decide
anything on his own!
挑発 挑発
超見え見えの挑発っす
He's just taunting you.
He's obviously provoking you.
来いよ カイジ
Come on, Kaiji!
弱気になって座り込んでも
星は増えねえぞ
The stars won't increase even
if you sit there in fear!
さあ 行きましょう カイジさん
Come on, let's go, Kaiji.
いや 下がれない
No... I won't back down!
What?
やつの言うとおりだ
下がっても星は増えない
He's right! The stars won't
increase if we back down!
何 言ってんの　星１つなんですよ
What are you saying?
You have only one star!
よしてよ カイジさん
勘弁してよ
- Give it up, Kaiji!
- Give me a break!
バカ　なぜ俺の演技が
分からない？
Idiot! Why can't you see
that I'm acting?
演技？
２戦目の負けは計算 まき餌だ
Acting?
The loss in the 2nd duel...
...was a calculated bait!
Now the fish is biting!
今 魚がエサに食いついたんだ
安心しろ　２連勝だよ
Don't worry,
it'll be 2 straight wins!
２連勝なんて どこにそんな勝算
あるんですか？
Two straight wins?
Why is he so confident?
こっちにチョキしかない以上…
With only Scissors cards
on our side,
相手が２回続けて
パーを出すってことだ
the opponent has to
put out 2 Paper in a row.
そんなの あり得ないっすよ
That's impossible.
カイジさんには確信があるんだろ
But Kaiji is confident.
確かにバランス派のハイエナが
Indeed, a balance type
like that guy...
この後 ２連続パーを出すとは
考えにくい
...isn't likely to put out
2 Paper cards back to back.
仮に出すとしたら それは
Even if he would,
it's only when he's sure
Kaiji would put Rock.
カイジがグーを出すと確信した時
あるいはパーを出しておけば
安心と考えた時である
Or when he feels that
it's safe to use Paper.
それはつまり…
Which means...
古畑さん？
安藤　カイジさん 勝つよ
Furuhata?
Ando! Kaiji will win.
やつは２度 続けてパーを出す
What?
He'll put 2 Paper consecutively.
どういうことっすか？
What do you mean?
やつのバランス理論だよ
It's his balance theory.
次の３戦目でよみがえったのさ
His rule for balancing his deck
comes into play in the next duel!
やつのバランス理論が
だからカイジさんを
執拗に勝負に誘った
That's why he tried so hard
to get Kaiji to play!
バランス理論がよみがえった？
The balance theory comes
into play?
２度続けてチョキを出した
カイジさんの
Will he even imagine
that Kaiji...
残りのカードが
２枚ともチョキだなんて
...is left with 2 Scissors after
using 2 Scissors in a row?
やつがそんな想像すると思うか？
やつは１戦目の時に
He probably thought that the cards
Kaiji had in the first duel...
カイジさんのカードの内訳は
チョキ２枚
そしてグーとパーが１枚ずつと
考えたはずだ
will be 2 Scissors, 1 Rock
and 1 Paper.
となれば
今 カイジさんの残りカードは
If that's the case,
he'd predict that...
グーとパーが１枚ずつ もしくは
どちらか２枚と考えている
...Kaiji has 1 Rock and 1 Paper,
or 2 cards of one type left.
つまり３戦目以降は
パーさえ出せば勝てる
Which means that as long as
he uses Paper, we win!
悪くてもあいこ
負けはないと確信したんだ
And at the very worst, we draw.
He believes he won't lose.
そうか
I see!
Kaiji waited until that guy believed
in that scenario to fight it out.
カイジさんは やつがその思考に
至るのを待って
勝負にいったんだ
チェック
Check.
そう　カイジは待った
Yes. Kaiji had waited for this.
敵が自らぬかるみに
足を踏み入れるのを
He kept his head down
to wait for the enemy...
顔を伏して待った
セット
...to get himself into a fix.
Set!
死ね　クズ
Die, garbage!
この待ちこそが
カイジのファインプレー
This waiting game was
fine play by Kaiji indeed!
地獄に落ちろ
Meet your doom! Open!
オープン
バ… バカな… どうして？
N-No way! Why...
じゃあな
ま… 待て
See ya!
Wait!
もうひと勝負だ
そうだ　戻れ カイジ
One more time!
Yeah! Come back, Kaiji!
古畑さん
Furuhata!
バランス理論の内にひそむ
ぬかるみ
The bog that lurks within
the theory of balance...
１度 深くはまった足は
たやすく抜けない
It's difficult to get out
once you're in it.
なぜならバランスが
思考を支配する
With balance dominating
one's thinking,
その世界観 理論 常識では
手持ちカードが
the idea that all the cards
are Scissors...
...totally defies his common sense,
theory and perspective!
すべてチョキなどということは
あり得ない
そんなこと 考えられない
That's why he'll never
believe in that.
チェック
もうチョキは出ない
Check.
There won't be any more Scissors.
セット
４枚チョキだけは絶対にない
Set.
He can't possibly have 4 Scissors!
オープン
Open!
３連続で同じ手が来たから
Having gone through
the same thing thrice,
もう同じ手は来ない
there's no way it would
happen again.
ギャンブルでは
この考え方は最も危険
This kind of thinking is the most
dangerous in gambling.
チョキはない　チョキは…
There's no Scissors!
No Scissors...
はまり込み
抜けられない崩壊への道
There's no escape from the path to
destruction once you're trapped.
ギャンブルという魔性が
せせら笑う
The devilish nature of gambling
mocked him in the face.
どうしてなんだ
Why is that so?!
Why are all 4 cards...!
どうして４枚も？
偶然さ
偶然… 偶然だと？
It was just a coincidence.
Coincidence? Coincidence?!
つまり あんたの読み…
理論は間違ってなんかいない
There's no mistake in your
prediction theoretically!
でも一歩狂えば そこが盲点だ
But if you miss a step,
your blind spot appears.
人間は理論ってやつを
１度 正しいと信じ込んじまうと
Once one believes that
a theory is true,
なかなか疑わなくなる
it's difficult to doubt it.
ましてや その理論で
勝ってきたやつとなれば
It's even more so for someone
who used that theory to win.
なおさら…
His belief in the theory
made him defenseless!
理論あるが故に無防備
カイジ 理論を逆手に取った２連勝
Kaiji used that to his advantage
to gain 2 straight wins.
だが 彼らを待ち受ける運命は
But the destiny waiting
for them is still dark,
まだ暗く出口は見えない
without a slit of light.
この無限に続く
漆黒の闇のように…
Like an infinite tunnel
of darkness...
次回｢破綻｣
Next, Failure.